webcarhire.com 2016-03-15

# Webcarhire : Privacy Policy

**Privacy Statement**

**YOUR PRIVACY**  
We value your participation and understand the importance of your personal information.

We recognise your trust in webcarhire.com when providing us with personal information as well as your right to privacy and control over your transactional details.

We take your right to privacy seriously and are committed to protecting and only using your personal information appropriately.

We collect both personal and payment information from you, only in order to be able to deliver the appropriate service you have requested from us. Information requested from you during any function on our site, is the minimum required in order to effectively deliver our services.

**INFORMATION ABOUT SITE VISITORS**  
Our web site will record information about your visit, including your server address, your top level domain name (ie. .com, .au, .uk etc), the date and time of your visit to the web site, the pages you accessed and documents you have downloaded, the previous site you have visited and the type of browser you are using. Web site statistics are generated from the web logs.

This information is anonymous. It cannot be and is not linked to you as an individual.

We use this information to review use of our web site and help determine the best way to meet our customer expectations.

**TRANSACTIONAL INFORMATION**

**If you do not log in as a WEBCARPLUS member**  
If you decide to obtain a quotation or make a care hire reservation on our web site, we will collect and record a minimum, appropriate amount of personal information from you at each stage in the process. This enables us to deliver the service requested.

In order to deliver to you the services you have requested from our web site, we collect the following information about you.

**Quotations**  
The personal information we collect when you request a car rental Quotation includes your pickup and dropoff details, the vehicle you have requested, your name and email address.

Your pickup and dropoff details enable us to provide the requested car hire quotation and personal details collected during this process will enable us to communicate with you in relation to this request. If you decide not to proceed with the quotation, your details are not used for any other purpose.

**Reservations**  
When you request a car hire reservation we will require further personal information, including your address, telephone number and your full credit card details, to confirm your reservation. Some information is optional, such as your Driver's License details.

Your details are then passed electronically from our web site to the nominated car rental company in order to deliver you the service requested. All data being transmitted between us and car rental companies is securely encrypted.

We record and encrypt and securely store all personal and transactional information you provide when you complete any of these processes.

During these processes we use "sessional" cookies to assist us in providing a fluent service to you. When you close your web browser, this sessional cookie is deleted and no personal information is maintained on your computer system which might identify you, even if you were to visit the site again at a later time.

**If you log in as a WEBCARPLUS member**  
When you first register as a **WEBCAR PLUS** member we collect personal information from you.

This information includes your name, email address and country.

We offer registered members the option of pre-storing, further personal information which is used during the reservation process to offer a faster service. This information includes your address and driver's license details and, whether you would like to receive on-going information from **WEBCARHIRE.COM**. We do not pre-store your credit card payment details.

On registration as a **WEBCAR PLUS** member we store on your computer a "persistent" cookie file. This cookie file does not contain any confidential data about you. The contents of the cookie are only relevant and meaningful to this website. It enables us to recognise you as a member and provide you with member services without the need to log in at each visit. It may also be used to profile and track your browsing behaviour on our web site and use this information to enhance our services to you or deliver additional membership benefits.

**COOKIES**  

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies (Google Analytics) to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes.

We also use Google cookies for remarketing to advertise online.

How does our remarketing activity affect you?

  * When you visit our website, our web server will drop a cookie on your browser
  * If you leave our website to visit another website which is part of the Google network, you may be served our ad
  * The remarketing cookie will be valid for 30 days

You can remove our remarketing cookie by deleting your Internet browsing history and clearing your cookies. This can be done through the tools/settings function of your Internet browser.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website. You can opt out of Google's use of cookies by visiting Google's Ad Settings. Alternatively you can opt out of a third-party vendors use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) opt out page.

There are two types of cookies used. " _Sessional_ " cookies are temporary files that help us track your details during the quoting and reservation functions and deliver a fluent service to you. These cookies are removed from your computer system when you close your browser. 

" _Persistent_ " cookies are used when you register as a **WEBCAR PLUS** member. These cookies are stored on your computer system's hard drive and enable us to identify member visits to the site and deliver member based benefits.

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies but you may change the settings of your browser to refuse cookies [please refer to the Help files of your browser for more information on changing settings].

Not accepting cookies may mean that you cannot receive the full benefits or services provided by our web site.

**USE AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**  
 **WEBCARHIRE.COM** will not disclose your personal information or access your communications on our web site without your consent or unless,

  * required by law  

  * it is necessary in providing you with a service you have requested

We do share your personal information with specific car rental companies where you have requested us to make a reservation on your behalf and, service providers such as our payment gateway which process all our credit card transactions.

We will not send you any promotional information unless you have specifically requested us to keep you informed about webcarhire.com or you have subscribed to specific promotions we offer.

When users choose to join a specific mailing list to receive publications or information, their details are added to that specific mailing list and reserved for dissemination for that purpose only.

If you have subscribed to receive further on-going information from us and no longer wish to receive our material, you may request to have your name removed from our lists.

**STORING PERSONAL INFORMATION  
WEBCARHIRE.COM** takes all reasonable steps to protect and secure all transactional and personal information which we hold about you.

Your personal and payment information is encrypted and stored on secure servers.

As a consumer on our site using our services you can help preserve the security and integrity of your information by not revealing your password details and notifying us of any unauthorised use of your details.
